

# Marco Richetta

- ♦ Copenhagen, Denmark
   □ marcorichetta@gmail.com
- marcorichetta.vercel.app | in marco-richetta | ; marcorichetta

### **About Me**

I like to share knowledge by giving talks, also as a mentor or simply helping others to solve problems. <u>E.g. the Django forum</u>.

Currently interested in enhancing **Developer Experience (DX)** through IaC. Also learning about Go, MLOps, Elixir.

My background is in backend but I like to look at the bigger picture and think beyond my specific role. Curiosity drives me but I'm always learning to balance it and prioritize impact.

## Experience

**Software Engineer**, Mercado Libre - Córdoba, Argentina

Jul 2022 - Jun 2024

- Worked improving **Python DX**, maintaining tooling used by thousands of developers in the company. (General support, features, bugfixes, version deprecation).
- Building on our Python expertise, we led upgrades for over 1,000 outdated Java applications and libraries using <u>Large-Scale Code Changes</u>, managing the roadmap and collaborating with responsible teams to implement and monitor each update.

Software Developer, Flux IT - Córdoba, Argentina

Jan 2021 - Jun 2022

- Fullstack development (**React/Django**) to integrate 3rd party systems with internal company applications.
- Later, in a more **DevOps** role, I helped in the migration of the internal infrastructure to Kubernetes applying **GitOps**. This also led to better DX.

#### Education

**BS** Computer Systems Analyst, Instituto Superior 25 de Mayo – Feb 2015 - Dec 2020 Córdoba, Argentina

# Volunteering

**Hack Your Future:** Joined as a Technical mentor to help people kickstart their programming carreers. - <a href="https://www.hackyourfuture.dk/">https://www.hackyourfuture.dk/</a>

# **Technologies**

Languages: Python, React, JavaScript/Typescript, Go

**Technologies:** Django, Pytest, Kubernetes, FluxCD, Docker, OpenTelemetry